howmanysyllables.com 2016-12-20

# Privacy Policy

Updated: **08/30/2016**

Download as PDF

 **Welcome to HowManySyllables.com, best known as How  Many Syllables.**

 _How  Many Syllables_ respects your privacy. This Privacy Policy is specific to HowManySyllables.com, its subdomains, its co-sponsored websites, our social media pages, and any other website or application, owned or operated by _How  Many Syllables_.

Section 1: General Terms and Agreement

1.1 Any reference to "we", "us", or "our" is a reference to _How  Many Syllables_, a corporation organized under the laws of the State of New York of the United States of America.

1.2 Any reference to "site", "website", or "apps" is a reference to HowManySyllables.com, its subdomains, co-sponsored websites, desktop applications, mobile apps, social media pages, or any other websites or applications that are owned or operated by _How  Many Syllables_.

1.3 Any reference to our "products", "features", or "services" is a reference to any of our dictionaries, databases, word-lists, media files, downloadable files, audio (sound) files or any other products, services, or features which are owned or operated by _How  Many Syllables_.

1.4 Any reference to our "social media pages" is a reference to our [Facebook page](https://www.facebook.com/HowManySyllables), our [Twitter page](https://twitter.com/WeKnowSyllables), our [Google Plus page](https://plus.google.com/+HowManySyllables), and any other pages which exist on any third-party website which are owned or operated by _How  Many Syllables_.

1.5 Any reference to "you", "your", or "user" is a reference to you (either as an individual or corporate entity), as a user who establishes a connection to our website or social media pages.

 **By using our site, you acknowledge that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy, and give consent to _How  Many Syllables_ to collect, use, and distribute data about you and your use of our site and social media pages as described below.**

Section 2: Statistical Information About Your Visit

2.1 When a user visits our site or uses our apps, we automatically collect statistical information about their visit. This information will _NOT_ be used to identify you personally, as an individual. It will be used to help us make site improvements and provide you with a better website and advertising experience. Your personal information will _NOT_ be shared with any third-parties. See Section 3, Section 4, and Section 5 for more details.

The information we collect includes, but is not limited to:

  * Your IP address
  * When you accessed our site
  * The words you looked up
  * Which page(s) and feature(s) you accessed on our site
  * How you used these feature(s)
  * Which interactive activities (such as games) you engaged with
  * How you interacted with our interactive activities (such as games)
  * Your responses to polling questions
  * How long you visited each page or engaged with a feature
  * The ads you clicked on
  * The URL of the page which referred you to us
  * Technical information about your computer or mobile device _(such as your browser, device, & operating system)_

2.2 _How  Many Syllables_ reserves the right at all times to use your statistical information to personally identify you (and all of your activity on our site and social media pages) when we believe it is appropriate to investigate or report illegal activity, comply with the law, satisfy a government request, defend against claims, enforce our site policies, or protect or enforce the rights, property, or safety for us or our users.

Section 3: Information You Choose to Provide

3.1 You may choose to contact us privately using our Contact Us page, by sending an email, or through the private message feature of a third-party website such as Facebook or Twitter. Personal information submitted in this way will only be used to provide you with the specific information requested or to address your specific query.

3.2 You may also choose to post a message in a public forum such as on the wall of our [ Facebook page](https://www.facebook.com/HowManySyllables), our [Twitter page](https://twitter.com/WeKnowSyllables), or our [Google Plus page](https://plus.google.com/+HowManySyllables). Please be aware that these are _public forums_ and your posts will be visible for the whole world to see. Private messages are an exception. They will be used to address your specific query and then archived or deleted. If you are concerned about a post which you have made, please use our Contact Us page to request that it be removed.

Section 4: How We Use Your Information

4.1 We may use your statistical information (see Section 2) to make site improvements and provide you with a better website experience, which includes but is not limited to providing you with advertisements that are relevant to you.

4.2 We do not sell or trade your personally identifiable information with third-parties. We may share your information with trusted third-parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. See Section 4 and Section 5 for more details.

4.3 We may choose to share non-personally identifiable (or aggregate) information about your site visit with third-parties or on our website. This data will _NOT_ identify you in any way.

 _For Example_ :

  * We will _NOT_ tell a third-party that John Q. Smith (JSmith@fakeEmail.com) visited our website on October 18th.
  * What we may say to them is that a user (unidentified to the third-party) visited our website on October 18th and looked up three words, one of which was "love."

4.4 We may choose to publicly disclose aggregate (non-personally identifiable) information about our users. This information may include, but is not limited to, the total number of visitors we get on a daily basis, what the most looked up words of the day are, how our users engaged with interactive activities on our site (such as games), and aggregate responses to polling questions found on our site or social media pages.

4.5 We may choose to publicly disclose any communication which we receive from you, or send to you, through email, private message(s) on our social media pages, or through our Contact Us page. We will _always_ remove your personal information from all such disclosures, unless we receive your consent to include it.

 _For Example_ :

  * We may publicly disclose that Amy (no last name) contacted us and asked why the word "orange" is 2 syllables.
  * We will _NEVER_ publicly disclose that John Q. Smith (JSmith@fakeEmail.com) contacted us and asked why the word "motion" has 2 syllables.
  * If we receive your permission, we may publicly disclose that Amy Smith, a teacher in New York City, won one of our contests.

4.6 We may disclose your personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, defend against claims, enforce our site policies, investigate or report illegal activity, or protect/enforce the rights, property, or safety for us or our users.

4.7 We may also transfer your information to another company in connection with a corporate restructuring, such as a sale or merger, or in the event of a bankruptcy proceeding.

Section 5: Third Parties

5.1 We do _NOT_ sell or trade your personally identifiable information to third-parties. We may share your information with trusted third-parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.

5.2 Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

5.3 Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-parties have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and request that you contact us if you experience any issues.

5.4 You assume the entire risk for a negative outcome experienced by clicking or engaging with an advertisement which takes you to a landing page or website not owned or operated by us. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and request that you contact us if you experience any issues.

5.5 _How  Many Syllables_ does not endorse any of the products being advertised on our site unless expressly written.

Section 6: California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

6.1 Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personally identifiable information to outside parties without your consent.

6.2 We may disclose your personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, defend against claims, enforce our site policies, investigate or report illegal activity, or protect/enforce the rights, property, or safety for us or our users.

Section 7: Use of Tracking Technologies

7.1 _Cookie_ : A cookie is a small text file placed on your computer that can allow us to recognize you and provide you with a better, more customized experience. We may use cookies to store your preferences and track your activity on our site.

7.2 _Pixel Tags_ : A pixels tag is a small, usually invisible, graphic that is placed in an email, on a website, or in an app. We may use pixel tags to access cookies (or vice versa) or to track your activity around our site. We may also use them to see whether or not an email we’ve sent has been opened.

7.3 _Third-party Advertising_ : Third-party vendors and advertising networks (including Google) use cookies to show you ads based on your prior visits to our website and other sites on the internet that are affiliated with the advertising network.

7.4 We may use Google’s advertising network to provide you with relevant advertisements. Google uses the DoubleClick cookie. It enables Google and its partners to show ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. You may opt-out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for internet-based advertising by visiting Google’s [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/).

7.5 We may also use additional third-party advertising networks to provide you with an optimized advertising experience. These advertising networks may use cookies of their own. Please visit the Privacy Policies of the individual networks for more details.

7.6 Many advertising companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative. NAI members allow users to opt-out of being tracked by cookies. To opt-out of cookie tracking by NAI members, you may visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and click on the "Consumer Opt-out" button. Companies may also be members of the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA"). To opt-out of cookie tracking by DAA members, you may visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

7.7 By using our website, our apps, our products, our services, or our social media pages, you give _How  Many Syllables_ explicit consent and grant permission to place cookies and other tracking technologies on your computer or mobile device.

Section 8: COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) Compliance

8.1 We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act). We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under 13 years old.

 ** _NOTE_** : Our Contact Us page does collect a user's name and email address. This section is designed for people of all ages to ask us a question about our site. It allows users who struggle with counting _the number of syllables in a word_ to ask our team a question and receive an explanation. Collecting a user's name and email address are an essential part of this feature. All of the personally identifiable information such as a name and email address that is entered in this section of the site will be archived or deleted once the question/inquiry is answered or once the information is provided to the user. Also, note that this feature is completely optional and is not a requirement for using our site.

 ** _NOTE TO PARENTS_ :** A parent or legal guardian may review all personal information inadvertently submitted by a child, ask to have it deleted, and refuse to allow any further collection or use of the child's information. If you are a parent or legal guardian and would like to review or remove the personal information inadvertently submitted by your child, please contact us.

Section 9: Information from Users Outside the United States of America

9.1 Our company and our data servers are located in the United States of America. Please be aware that your information will be sent to and stored in the United States. By using our website, our apps, our services, or our social media pages, you agree to the information collection, use, and sharing practices described in this Privacy Policy.

Section 10: Changes to Our Privacy Policy

10.1 We may change our privacy policy for any reason and at any time, with or without prior notice. We will notify users of changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the revised version at www.HowManySyllables.com/privacy and updating the "Updated" date. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately.

Questions

If you have any questions, please use the Contact Us page to send us a message.
